Guide to the Waldron W. Boger scrap book AD.MC.155
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
Waldron W. Boger scrap book
1941-1946
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
Boger, Waldron W. (William), 1915-1990
AD.MC.155
0.10 Linear Feet in one album, 37 pages (20 leaves), housed in 1 document box.
One scrap book, containing photographs, correspondence, documents, telegrams, newspaper clippings and ephemera related to the military service of Lieutenant Waldron W. Boger, of the U.S. Army, documenting his service during and after World War II, from training camps in Utah and Texas, to his deployment with the Persian Gulf Command in Iran in 1944, and his service in the Phillipines in late 1945, prior to his discharge and transition into reserve status in March 1946.
Conditions governing access
The collection is open for use in the Reading Room of the Archives and Special Collections department of the NYU Abu Dhabi Library.
Immediate source of acquisition
Acquired by purchase, April 2019.
Arrangement
The contents of the scrapbook are in their original order and appearance, including housing groups of photos in envelopes supplied by the owner of the scrapbook. Although the scrapbook is unpaginated, the description in the finding aid assigns page numbers and provides brief descriptions of the contents of each page. Some pages are left blank, and not reflected in the inventory.
Biographical note
Waldron William Boger was born in Dillon, Montana on 22 January 1915. He studied pharmacy at the University of Montana, from which he graduated in 1937. In October 1939, he married Louise Davison in Deer Lodge, Montana. In late 1942 he received a draft notice and in early 1943 was inducted into the U.S. Army, and during that year he received training at Camp Douglas in Salt Lake City, Utah, and at Camp Barkeley, near Abilene Texas. In early 1944, he was assigned to the Persian Gulf Command, with the rank of Private First Class,serving in the 256th Station Hospital, initially based in Abadan, Iran before moving to Qazvin in mid-1944. In early 1945 he returned to Camp Barkeley for Officer Training School, and after completion and promotion to the rank of 2nd Lieutenant, he was sent to the Phillipines, where he served in medical administration until the end of that year. He returned to the United States in March 1946, when he was demobilized from active service but commissioned to the Army reserves. Not much is known about his later life, other than that he had one daughter, Kathy, and died in August 1990 in Napa, California.
Content Description
One scrap book, containing photographs, correspondence, documents, telegrams, newspaper clippings and ephemera related to the military service of Lieutenant Waldron W. Boger, of the U.S. Army, documenting his service during and after World War II, from training camps in Utah and Texas, to his deployment with the Persian Gulf Command in Iran in 1944, and his service in the Phillipines in late 1945, prior to his discharge and transition into reserve status in March 1946.
United States. -- Persian Gulf Command.; Iran -- Description and travel; Qazvin, Iran; Tehran, Iran
- Fort Douglas, Salt Lake: three snapshots, two news clippings, two draft notices, 1941-1943 (Volume 1, Page 1)
- Fort Douglas: five photographic prints, of Boger and other soldiers, July 3, 1943 (Volume 1, Page 2)
- Photographs: portrait of Boger in uniform, two photographs of Louise (one captioned "war widows"), and fragment of letter, undated, circa 1943 (Volume 1, Page 3)
- Camp Barkeley, Texas: photographs (5) depicting scenes of camp and images of Boger, undated, circa 1943 (Volume 1, Page 4)
- One photograph, portraying soldiers at Camp Barkeley during training, and one certificate of purchase of war bonds, August 1943 and undated (Volume 1, Page 5)
- Printed program (1 leaf), from recital by singer Marie Houston, at Camp Barkeley, July 23, 1943 (Volume 1, Page 6)
- Excerpts of two letters from Waldron Boger to Louise Boger, July 25-26, 1943 (Volume 1, Page 7)
- Excerpts of letters (3), from Waldron Boger to Louise Boger, plus temporary identification form, July 8 - 20, 1943 (Volume 1, Page 8)
- One form: War Department. "Application for Dependency Benefits," typescript, June 26, 1943 (Volume 1, Page 9)
- One form: Veterans Administration. "Application for National Service Life Insurance," typescript, June 28, 1943 (Volume 1, Page 10)
- Correspondence: packet of letters sent by Waldron Boger to Louise Boger, between, January 1944 - November 1945 (Volume 1, Page 11)
- Flyer: mess hall menu, Headquarters, Replacement Command, U.S. Army Forces Western Pacific, January 1, 1946 (Volume 1, Page 12)
- Program: "Salute to Gershwin," Palm Grove Theatre, 360th Station Hospital, December 3, 1945 (Volume 1, Page 13)
- Memorandum: Headquarters, 256th Station Hospital, Persian Gulf Command, announcing promotions, including that of Waldron Boger to rank of Private First Class, affixed to page with cloth chevrons [news clipping and other document on verso], June 20, 1944 (Volume 1, Page 14)
- Various: luggage tag, shore-leave pass, one envelope containing bottle labels from Soviet beverages purchased while in Iran, and one envelope containing V-Mail letters sent from Boger to his wife, plus one photograph, February - April 1944 (Volume 1, Page 15)
- Cloth armbands and shoulder patches: includes armband for medical personnel (with Red Cross symbol), insignia of the Persian Gulf Command, and others, undated, circa 1944 (Volume 1, Page 16)
- Banknotes (5): from Japanese-occupied Philippines and Dutch East Indies, as well as one from Allied occupied Italy, undated, circa 1942-1944 (Volume 1, Page 17)
- Banknotes (2): from Russia (1000 rubles) and Morocco (50 francs), undated (Volume 1, Page 18)
- Banknotes (10): from Japanese-occupied Philippines, American-occupied Philippines, Iran, and Morocco, 1943-1944 and undated (Volume 1, Page 19)
- Typescript text, 1 leaf: "Somewhere in Asia" [anonymous poem], undated, circa 1944 (Volume 1, Page 20)
- Two documents: announcement of examination for appointment to the Pharmacy Corps of the U.S. Army, and letter of reference on Boger's behalf, January - March 1944 (Volume 1, Page 21)
- Magazine excerpt: cover and tear sheet from "Time" magazine, Far East edition, featuring cover story of Mohamed Reza Pahlavi, Shah of Iran, December 17, 1945 (Volume 1, Page 22)
- Various: news clipping from military newspaper, Daily Pacifica, with soldiers' letters to the editor, and printed ephemera, 1946 and undated (Volume 1, Page 23)
- Documents (4): three medical documents related to Boger, and one change-of-station order, July - October 1944 (Volume 1, Page 24)
- Photographs (5): Boger and colleagues from 256th Station Hospital, including group portrait and one of Boger, in front of recreation center in Tehran, undated, circa 1944 (Volume 1, Page 25)
- Photographs (30 prints), in envelope affixed to page: various images of scenery and people in Iran, including Tehran, Qom, Qasvin, undated, circa 1944 (Volume 1, Page 26)
- Photographs (18 prints), in envelope, affixed to page: scenery and people around Tehran and Qazvin, undated, circa 1944 (Volume 1, Page 27)
- Telegrams (36), in envelope affixed to page: messages between Waldron and Louise Boger, 1943-1946 (Volume 1, Page 29)
- Booklet (detached from page): "Recreation Center Tours: For the information and guidance of personnel visiting the recreation center," US Army, Persian Gulf Command (stapled, 27 pages), undated, circa 1944 (Volume 1, Page 30)
- Photographs (6): Waldron Boger, with wife Louise, and Rollins family, while on leave in Seattle and Abilene, undated, circa early 1945 (Volume 1, Page 31)
- Photographs (2) and news clippings: Photographs depicting Fort Lewis, Tacoma, Washington; and news clippings announcing Boger's visit to family during leave, undated, circa early 1945 (Volume 1, Page 32)
- Ephemera (3): printed list of graduates from officer's training class, Camp Barkeley; map of Pacific Ocean, showing route of Boger's subsequent voyage, and card commemorating crossing the 180th Meridian, March - July 1945 (Volume 1, Page 33)
- Booklets, printed (2): program for graduation exercises, Medical Administrative Corps, Officer Candidate School, Camp Barkeley; printed menu for dinner following ceremony, March 1945 (Volume 1, Page 34)
- Documents (6): related to Boger's promotion to rank of 2nd Lieutenant, and his subsequent commissioning as an officer in the Reserve Corps of the U.S. Army, December 1945 - April 1946 (Volume 1, Page 35)
- News clippings (6): announcing Boger's home leave, birth of daughter, and promotion in rank, undated, circa February - December 1945 (Volume 1, Page 36)
- Photographs (4): depicting war-time damage, in and around Manila, undated, circa 1945 (Volume 1, Page 37)
- Photographs (4): depicting war-time damage, in and around Manila, undated, circa 1945 (Volume 1, Page 39)